http://www.leica-geosystems.com/global/privacy-policy

Home
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Leica Geosystems AG, (“Leica Geosystems” or “we” or “us”) respect your privacy. Leica Geosystems is committed to the safe and secure processing of personal data and compliance with applicable data protection law.  We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect your personal data against loss or unlawful access.  The number of persons with access to your personal data is limited. Only individuals associated with Leica Geosystems that need to process your personal data in accordance with the purposes below will have access to your personal data.
The following describes how we process your personal data.
HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA
Fulfilling our contractual obligations towards your company, for example sending quotes, order administration, provision of products and services to your company, invoicing your company, responding to your service requests, etc.
How do we obtain your personal data
We obtain personal data from you when you register on our Web Sites, furnish our representatives with your business card, or when we obtain your data from representatives of your company.
Categories of personal data we process
Personal master data (key personal data);
Contact data;
Key contract data (Contractual/Legal Relationships, Contractual or Product Interest);
Network and device identification.
The purposes of the processing
Fulfilling our contractual obligations towards your company, e.g., sending quotes, order administration, provision of products and services to your company, invoicing your company, responding to your service requests etc.
Legal basis for the processing
It is within the legitimate interest of Leica Geosystems and your company to process your personal data for the above noted purposes. We use your personal data for fulfilling our contractual obligations towards your company. The privacy impact of the processing is low, as Leica Geosystems contacts you in your professional capacity.
Recipients (or categories of recipients) of the personal data
We will share your personal data with companies within the Hexagon Group.
We will also share your personal data with suppliers and business partners and legal agents which carry out services on our behalf such as customer relationship management solution providers and travel agents.
Retention period
We will retain your data for as long as the business relationship with your company exists and for as long as your employment with your company subsists. We will retain and use your data during the applicable statutory limitation periods and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and to enforce agreements.
Marketing/Prospecting:
How we have obtained your personal data
You provided your personal data through the use of our Web Sites (eg. registration form completion allowing the placement of cookies). We may have received your personal data when you supplied us with your business card, or we may have obtained your personal data from your company. Personal data may also be obtained from third party data augmentation services. You may have provided us with personal data over the telephone. If you have registered to attend an event with a third party provider, then we may obtain your personal data from that third party provider, where you have given your consent to such third party provider to supply your personal data to us.
Categories of personal data we process
Personal master data (key personal data);
Contact data;
Key contract data (Contractual/Legal Relationships, Contractual or Product Interest);
Network and device identification.
The purposes of the processing
Informing you via any means (including via email, telephone, text message, social media, post, or in person) about our products, services, publications and events which we think may be of interest to you and your company, based on previous purchases and interest shown in Leica Geosystems products and services.
Legal basis for the processing
Unless we explicitly request your consent to process your personal data, we rely on Leica Geosystems and your company’s legitimate interest to send you relevant marketing communications. The privacy impact of the processing of your personal data is low, as Leica Geosystems contacts you in your professional capacity. You can opt out of processing for direct marketing purposes by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link situated within any marketing emails sent to you. You also have the right to object to the processing at any time by contacting Email: privacy.geo@hexagon.com. Where you withdraw your consent or unsubscribe (as applicable), we will retain certain personal data (only to the extent that it is absolutely required) on our “do not contact” list.
Recipients (or categories of recipients) of the personal data
We will share your personal data with companies within the Hexagon Group.
We will also share your personal data with suppliers and business partners and legal agents that carry out services on our behalf such as marketing solution providers.
Retention period
We will process your personal data unless you opt out of the processing for direct marketing purposes.
Customers Testimonials, Comments and Reviews:
How we have obtained your personal data
We obtain your personal data through the completion of a release document which is available in hard copy and is also available online.
Categories of personal data we process
Contact details, job role and key personal data.
The purposes of the processing
The processing is required for the purpose of providing reviews to our client base in support or otherwise, of our products, services and software.
Legal basis for the processing
We have obtained your prior, informed consent to the processing.
Recipients (or categories of recipients) of the personal data
Individuals who access any marketing channel from either within Leica Geosystems or outside of Leica Geosystems.
Retention period
For as long as is necessary unless you withdraw your consent to the processing.
**Where Leica Geosystems has sought your consent to the processing of your personal data then you can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting Email: privacy.geo@hexagon.com.
TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA TO THIRD COUNTRIES
Your personal data may be transferred to a country outside of EU/EEA such as Canada (commercial organizations), New Zealand and Switzerland, which offer similar level of protection as within the EU/EEA. The transfer is based on the legal basis outlined in HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA and is for the purpose outlined in HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA. The transfer to these countries is based on the adequacy decision of the European Commission.
Your personal data may be transferred to a country outside of EU/EEA such as Australia, Brazil, Chile, China, Colombia, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Japan, Malaysia, Mexico, Peru, Philippines, Russia, Singapore, South Africa, South Korea, Taiwan, Thailand, UAE, United States, Venezuela, which may have a lower level of protection than within the EU/EEA. The transfer is based on the legal basis outlined in HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA and is for the purpose outlined in HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA.  When transferring personal data to these countries, Leica Geosystems uses standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission to ensure a sufficient level of protection of your personal data. The standard contractual clauses can be found via the following link: http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm.
WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS?
You are entitled to know what personal data we are processing about you. You have the right to request access to your personal data and you can request that we provide a copy of such data to you.  You are entitled to have incorrect personal data regarding you corrected, and in some cases you may request that we delete your personal data. You also have the right to object to certain processing of your personal data, and request that the processing of your personal data be limited. Limitation or deletion of your personal data may result in Leica Geosystems not being able to fulfil its commitments to you. You also have the right to request data portability, where your personal data would be extracted in a machine-readable format and transferred to another controller. Leica Geosystems may not always be obliged to comply with a request from you for deletion, restriction, objection or data portability. Additional circumstances such as exercising the right of freedom of expression and information, compliance with a legal obligation which requires processing by EU or Member State law or processing for establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims can justify further processing by Leica Geosystems.  Leica Geosystems will assess the eligibility of your request and inform you about Leica Geosystems decision and reasoning.  Where you have given us your consent to process your personal data, you can withdraw your consent at any time and without justification. Where you withdraw your consent, certain personal data (only to the extent that it is absolutely required), will be retained on our “do not contact” list.
If you have questions regarding how we process Personal Data concerning you, you are most welcome to contact us at Email: privacy.geo@hexagon.com.
OBJECTIONS AND COMPLAINTS
If you have any objections or complaints with the way in which we process your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant data protection supervisory authority, where the applicable laws provide for such remedy.
IDENTITY OF THE PRIVACY OFFICER
The Leica Geosystems Privacy Officer can be contacted at: privacy.geo@hexagon.com.
IDENTITY OF THE CONTROLLER
Hexagon AB, Swedish Company Registration Number 556190-4771, Lilla Bantorget 15, P.O. Box 3692, SE-103 59 Stockholm, Sweden (hexagon.com), its subsidiaries and controlled joint ventures are the controller(s) of your personal data.
Leica Geosystems operates within a matrix/division structure and utilises data processing tools shared between multiple Hexagon Group entities. It follows that your location and your business relationship with Leica Geosystems are essential in determining the relevant controller(s) in terms of the processing of your personal data within the Hexagon Group.
Upon your request to the Privacy Officer, you will be provided with full details of the relevant controller(s) within the Hexagon Group which is/are responsible for the processing of your personal data. We will provide the name and the contact details of any data protection officer where appointed by the applicable controller.
FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS ONLY
The purpose of this section is to provide information to California residents pursuant to the California Consumer Protection Act (CCPA).
Personal data includes also any information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a household.We do not and will not sell your personal data to third parties.
INFORMATION REGARDING COOKIES
Please see our Cookie Policy.
LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES
Our Web Site includes links to other Web Sites whose privacy practices may differ from those described in this Privacy Policy. If you submit personal information to any of those third party Web Sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the Privacy Policy of any Web Site you visit.
SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS
Our Web Site includes social media features, such as the “Facebook” button, and widgets, such as the “Share This” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Web Site. These features and widgets may collect your IP address, which page(s) you are visiting on our Web Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature or widget to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Web Site. Your interactions with these features and widgets are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
This Privacy Policy was last amended on July 28, 2020
Contact Leica Geosystems
Find your Leica Geosystems contact for sales, support and technical service.
Find your Leica Geosystems contact for sales, support and technical service.
Sales & Support
